<records>
<reference key="1">
	<details>Cave, B. and Curtis, S. (2001). Health impact assessment for regeneration projects. Volume I: A practical guide. Queen Mary, University of London and Regeneration Workstream, East London Health Action Zone. Available: Department of Geography, Queen Mary, University of London. http://www.geog.qmw.ac.uk/</details>
</reference>
<reference key="2">
	<details>Cave, B. and Curtis, S. (2001). Health impact assessment for regeneration projects. Volume III: Principles. Queen Mary, University of London and Regeneration Workstream, East London Health Action Zone. Available: Department of Geography, Queen Mary, University of London. http://www.geog.qmw.ac.uk/</details>
</reference>
<reference key="3">
	<details>Pawson, R. and Tilley, N. Realistic evaluation. London; Thousand Oaks, Calif., Sage. 1997: 1-235.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="4">
	<details>Pawson, R. and Tilley, N. Realistic evaluation. London; Thousand Oaks, Calif., Sage. 1997: 1-235.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="5">
	<details>Kirkwood, B. R. Essentials of medical statistics. Oxford, Blackwell Science Ltd. 1988: 1-234.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="6">
	<details>McCarthy, M. Transport and health in Social determinants of health Marmot, M. and Wilkinson, R. G., eds. Oxford, Oxford University Press. 1999: pp.132-154.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="7">
	<details>Roberts, I. and Power, C. Does the decline in child injury mortality vary by social class? A comparison of class specific mortality in 1987 and 1991. British Medical Journal,  313 (7060) pp.784-786, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="8">
	<details>Roberts, I., Li, L. et al. Trends in intentional injury deaths in children and teenagers (1980-1995). Journal of Public Health Medicine,  20 (4) pp.463-466, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="9">
	<details>Boyes, E. and Stannisstreet, M. Children's ideas about cars and health: An environmental motivator? Transportation Research Part D-Transport and Environment,  3 (2) pp.105-115, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="10">
	<details>McMichael, A. J. Transport and health: assessing the risks in Health at the crossroads: transport policy and urban health Fletcher, T. C. and McMichael, A. J., eds. London, John Wiley and Sons. 1997: pp.9-26.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="11">
	<details>British Medical Association. Cycling toward health and safety. London, Oxford University Press. 1992.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="12">
	<details>Pucher, J., Komanoff, C. et al. Bicycling renaissance in North America? Recent trends and alternative policies to promote bicycling. Transportation Research Part A-Policy And Practice,  33 (7-8) pp.625-654, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="13">
	<details>Rivara, F. P., Thompson, D. C. et al. Epidemiology of bicycle injuries and risk factors for serious injury. Injury Prevention,  3 pp.110-114, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="14">
	<details>Carlin, J. B., Stevenson, M. R. et al. Walking to school and traffic exposure in Australian children. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Public Health,  21 (3) pp.286-292, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="15">
	<details>Hillman, M., Adams, J. et al. One false move: a study of children's independent mobility. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1990.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="16">
	<details>Rowland, T. W. and Freedson, P. S. Physical activity, fitness and health in children: a closer look. Pediatrics,  93 pp.669-672, 1994</details>
</reference>
<reference key="17">
	<details>Paluska, S. A. and Schwenk, T. L. Physical activity and mental health - current concepts. Sports Medicine,  29 (3) pp.167-180, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="18">
	<details>Sleap, M. and Warburton, P. Physical activity levels of 5-11-year-old children in England: cumulative evidence from three direct observation studies. International Journal of Sports Medicine ,  17 (4) pp.482-258, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="19">
	<details>Rowlands, A. V. and Ingledew, D. K. Measurement of physical activity in children with particular reference to the use of heart rate and pedometry. Sports Medicine,  24 (4) pp.258-272, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="20">
	<details>British Medical Association. Road transport and health. London, British Medical Association. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="21">
	<details>Jarvis, S., Towner, E. et al. Accidents in The health of our children Botting, B., ed. London, Office of Population Censuses and Surveys, HMSO. 1995.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="22">
	<details>Robertson, H. K. Heart disease in life-long cyclists. British Medical Journal,  24-31 (1) pp.635-636, 1971</details>
</reference>
<reference key="23">
	<details>Acheson, D., Barker, D. et al. Independent inquiry into inequalities in health: report.  pp.1-164. 1998. London, The Stationery Office.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="24">
	<details>Bartley, M. J. Unemployment and ill health: understanding the relationship. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  48 pp.333-337, 1994</details>
</reference>
<reference key="25">
	<details>Wilkinson, R. G. and Marmot, M. The solid facts: social determinants of health. World Health Organisation.  pp.1-32. 1998. </details>
</reference>
<reference key="26">
	<details>Karasek, R. and Theorell, T. Healthy work: stress, productivity, and the reconstruction of working life.  1990. New York, Basic Books.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="27">
	<details>Burchell, B. J. The effects of labour market position, job insecurity and unemployment on psychological health in Social change and the experience of unemployment Gallie, D., Marsh, C. et al., eds. Oxford, New York, OUP. 1994.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="28">
	<details>Barnett, P. Unemployment, work and health: opportunities for healthy public policy. New Zealand Medical Journal,  108 (998), 1995</details>
</reference>
<reference key="29">
	<details>Stansfeld, S., Fuhrer, R. et al. Work characteristics predict psychiatric disorder: prospective results from the Whitehall II study. Occupational and Environmental Medicine,  56 (5) pp.302-307, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="30">
	<details>Brenner, M. H. Mortality and the economy: a review, and the experience of England and Wales, 1936-1976. Lancet ,  ii pp.568-573, 1979</details>
</reference>
<reference key="31">
	<details>Eyer.J. Prosperity as a cause of death. International Journal of Health Services,  7 pp.125-168, 1977</details>
</reference>
<reference key="32">
	<details>Gravelle, H., Hutchinson, G. et al. Mortality and unemployment: a critique of Brenner's time-series analysis. Lancet,  ii pp.657-679, 1981</details>
</reference>
<reference key="33">
	<details>Shortt, S. E. D. Is unemployment pathogenic? A review of current concepts with lessons for policy planners. International Journal of Health Services,  26 (3) pp.569-589, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="34">
	<details>Morrell, S., Taylor, R. J. et al. A cohort study of unemployment as a cause of psychological disturbance in Australian youth. Soc.Sci.Med.,  38 (11) pp.1553-1563, 1994</details>
</reference>
<reference key="35">
	<details>Strandh, M. Different exit routes from unemployment and their impact on mental well-being: the role of the economic situation and the predictability of the life course. Work, Employment and Society,  14 (3) pp.459-479, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="36">
	<details>Graetz, B. Health consequences of employment and unemployment: longitudinal evidence for young men and women. Soc.Sci.Med.,  36 (6) pp.715-724, 1993</details>
</reference>
<reference key="37">
	<details>Ritchie, J. Thirty families: their living standards in unemployment. Department of Social Security Research Report No.1. 1990. London, HMSO.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="38">
	<details>Bosma, H., Marmot, M. et al. Low job control and risk of coronary heart disease in Whitehall II (prospective cohort) study. British Medical Journal,  314 pp.558-565, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="39">
	<details>Bosma, H., Stansfeld, S. et al. Job control, personal characteristics, and heart disease. Journal of Occupational Health Psychology,  3 (4) pp.402-409, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="40">
	<details>Vahtera, J., Kivimaki, M. et al. Effect of change in the psychosocial work environment on sickness absence: a seven year follow up of initially healthy employees. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  54 pp.484-493, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="41">
	<details>Cobb, S. Physiological changes in men whose jobs were lost. Journal of Psychosomatic Research,  18 pp.245-258, 1974</details>
</reference>
<reference key="42">
	<details>Iversen, L. and Sabroe, S. Hospital admissions before and after shipyard closure. British Medical Journal,  299 pp.1073-1076, 1988</details>
</reference>
<reference key="43">
	<details>Joelson, L. and Wahlquist, L. The psychological meaning of job insecurity and job loss: results of a longitudinal study. Soc.Sci.Med.,  25 (2) pp.179-182, 1987</details>
</reference>
<reference key="44">
	<details>Mattiasson, I., Lindgarde, F. et al. The threat of unemployment and cardiovascular risk factors longitudinal study of quality of sleep and serum cholesterol concentrations in men threatened with redundancy. British Medical Journal,  301 pp.4, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="45">
	<details>Westin, S. The structure of factory closure: individual response to job loss and unemployment in a 10 year controlled follow up study. Soc.Sci.Med.,  31 pp.1301-1311, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="46">
	<details>Beale, N. and Nethercott, S. Job loss and family morbidity: a study of a factory closure. Journal of Royal College of General Practitioners,  35 pp.510-514, 1985</details>
</reference>
<reference key="47">
	<details>Beale, N. and Nethercott, S. The health of industrial employees four years after compulsory redundancy. Journal of Royal College of General Practitioners,  37 pp.390-394, 1987</details>
</reference>
<reference key="48">
	<details>Glenn, L., Beck, R. et al. Effect of a transient, geographically localised economic recovery on community health and income studied with longitudinal household cohort method. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  52 (11) pp.749-757, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="49">
	<details>Halvorsen, K. Impact of re-employment on psychological distress among long-term unemployed. Acta Sociologica,  41 pp.227-242, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="50">
	<details>Westerlund, H., Theorell, T. et al. Psychophysiological effects of temporary alternative employment. Social Science and Medicine,  52 (3 ) pp.405-415, 2001</details>
</reference>
<reference key="51">
	<details>Bolton, W. and Oatley, A. A longitudinal study of social support and depression in unemployed men. Psychological Medicine,  17 pp.453-460, 1987</details>
</reference>
<reference key="52">
	<details>Hammer, T. Unemployment and use of drugs and alcohol among young people: a longitudinal study in the general population. British Journal of Addiction,  84 pp.1571-1581, 1992</details>
</reference>
<reference key="53">
	<details>Peck, D. F. and Plant, M. A. Unemployment and illegal drug use: concordant evidence from a prospective study and and national trends. British Medical Journal,   pp.929-931, 1986</details>
</reference>
<reference key="54">
	<details>Hammer, T. Unemployment and mental health among young people: a longitudinal study. Journal of Adolescence,  16 pp.407-420, 1993</details>
</reference>
<reference key="55">
	<details>Murphy, G. C. and Athanasou, J. A. The effect of unemployment on mental health. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology,  72 pp.83-99, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="56">
	<details>Martikainen, P. T. Unemployment and mortality among Finnish men 1981-1985. British Medical Journal,  301 (6749) pp.407-411, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="57">
	<details>Moser, K. A., Goldblatt, P. O. et al. Unemployment and mortality: comparison of the 1971 and 1981 Longitudinal Study census sample. British Medical Journal,  294 pp.87-90, 1987</details>
</reference>
<reference key="58">
	<details>Frese, M. and Mohr, G. Prolonged unemployment and depression in older workers: a longitudinal study of intervening variables. Soc.Sci.Med.,  25 (2) pp.173-178, 1987</details>
</reference>
<reference key="59">
	<details>Schwefel, D. Unemployment, health and health services in German-speaking countries. Soc.Sci.Med.,  22 (4) pp.409-430, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="60">
	<details>Jin, R., Shah, C. et al. The impact of unemployment on health: A review of the evidence (Reprinted from Canadian Medical Association Journal, vol 153, pg 529-40, 1995). Journal of Public Health Policy,  18 (3) pp.275-301, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="61">
	<details>Lawless, P., Martin, R. et al.  Unemployment and social exclusion: landscapes of labour inequality. London, Jessica Kingley Publishers. 1998.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="62">
	<details>Nickell, S. and Bell, B. The collapse in demand for the unskilled and unemployment across the OECD. Oxford Review of Economic Policy: Unemployment,  11 pp.40-62, 1995</details>
</reference>
<reference key="63">
	<details>Payne, J. and Payne, C. Trends in job loss and recruitment in Britain 1979 - 1991 in Unemployment and public policy in a changing labour market White, M., ed. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1994.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="64">
	<details>Bethune, A. Unemployment and mortality in Health inequalities: decennial supplement: DS Series No.15 Drever, F. and Whitehead, M., eds. London, The Stationery Office. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="65">
	<details>Moser, K. A., Goldblatt, P. O. et al. Unemployment and mortality in Longitudinal Study 1971-1981: mortality and social organisation Goldblatt, P. O., ed. London, HMSO. 1990.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="66">
	<details>Moylan, S., Millar, J. et al. For richer, for poorer? Department of Health and Social Security cohort study of unemployed men. London, HMSO. 1984.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="67">
	<details>White, H. Long-term unemployment and labour markets. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1983.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="68">
	<details>Daniel, W. The unemployment flow. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1990.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="69">
	<details>Piachaud, D. A price worth paying? The costs of unemployment in Working for full employment Philpott, J., ed. London, Routledge. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="70">
	<details>Berthoud, R. The reform of supplementary benefit. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1984.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="71">
	<details>White, H. Against unemployment. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1991.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="72">
	<details>Bradshaw, J. Child poverty and deprivation in the UK. London, National Children's Bureau. 1990.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="73">
	<details>Montgomery, S. M., Bartley, M. J. et al. Health and social precursors of unemployment in young men in Great Britain. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  50 pp.415-422, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="74">
	<details>Wadsworth, M. E. J. The imprint of time: childhood, history and adult life. Oxford, Oxford University Press. 1991.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="75">
	<details>Sly, F., Duxbury, R. et al. Disability and the labour market: findings from the Labour Market Force Survey. Labour Market Trends,  December pp.439-457, 1995</details>
</reference>
<reference key="76">
	<details>The Carnegie United Kingdom Trust. The Carnegie Young People Initiative: years of decision. Leicester, Youth Work Press. 1996.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="77">
	<details>Chatrick, B. and Maclagan, I. Taking their chance: education, training and employment opportunities for young people. London, The Children's Society. 1995.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="78">
	<details>Dolton, P., Makepeace, G. et al. The Youth Training Scheme and the School-to-Work transition. Oxford Economic Papers,  46 pp.629-657, 1994</details>
</reference>
<reference key="79">
	<details>Lindley, R. The School-to-Work transition in the United Kingdom. London, International Labour Review. 1996.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="80">
	<details>Maclagan, I. A broken promise: the failure of youth training policy. London, Youthaid and The Children's Society. 1992.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="81">
	<details>Rolfe, H., Bryson, A. et al. The effectiveness of Training and Enterprise Councils in achieving jobs and qualifications for disadvantaged groups: Department for Education and Employment research study 4. London, HMSO. 1996.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="82">
	<details>Dennehy, A., Smith, I. et al. Not to be ignored: young people, poverty and health. London, Child Poverty Action Group. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="83">
	<details>Ratner, P. A. The incidence of wife abuse and mental health status in Edmonton, Alberta. Canadian Journal of Public Health,  84 pp.246-249, 1983</details>
</reference>
<reference key="84">
	<details>Gregg, P. and Wadsworth, M. E. J. A short history of labour turnover, job tenure and job security. Oxford Review of Economic Policy: Unemployment,  11 pp.73-90, 1995</details>
</reference>
<reference key="85">
	<details>Martin, R. Regional dimensions of Europe's unemployment crisis in Unemployment and social exclusion: landscapes of labour inequality Lawless, P., Martin, R. et al., eds. London, Jessica Kingley Publishers. 1998.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="86">
	<details>Pollert, A., ed. Farewell to flexibility? Oxford, Basil Blackwell. 1991: 1-316.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="87">
	<details>Prescott-Clarke, P. Employment and handicap. London, Social and Community Planning Research. 1990.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="88">
	<details>Health and Safety Executive. Self-reported work-related illness in 1995: results from a household survey. London, Health and Safety Executive Books. 1998.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="89">
	<details>Hemingway, H. and Marmot, M. Psychosocial factors in the aetiology and prognosis of coronary heart disease: a systematic review of prospective cohort studies in Evidence based cardiology Yusuf, S., Cairns, J. A. et al., eds. London, BMJ Books. 1998.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="90">
	<details>Marmot, M., Bosma, H. et al. Contributions of job control and other risk factors to social variations in coronary heart disease incidence. Lancet,  350 pp.235-239, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="91">
	<details>Hemingway, H., Shipley, M. et al. Sickness absence from back pain, psychosocial work characteristics and employment grade among office workers. Scandinavian Journal of Work, Environment and Health,  23 pp.121-129, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="92">
	<details>Emdad, R., Belkic, K. et al. Psychophysiologic sensitization to headlight glare among professional drivers with, and without, cardiovascular disease. Journal of Occupational Health Psychology,  3 pp.147-160, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="93">
	<details>Siegrist, J. Adverse health effects of high effort/low reward conditions. Journal of Occupational Health Psychology,  1 pp.27-41, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="94">
	<details>Karasek, R. Stress prevention through work reorganization: a summary of 19 international case studies in Preventing stress at work: conditions of work digest, volume II, No.2 International Labour Organisation, ed. Geneva, International Labour Organisation. 1992.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="95">
	<details>World Health Organisation. Health promotion in the workplace: strategy options. Copenhagen, World Health Organisation. 1995.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="96">
	<details>Health and Safety Executive. Stress at work: a guide for employers. London, Health and Safety Executive Books. 1995.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="97">
	<details>Division of Mental Health. Life skills education in schools.  1993. Geneva, World Health Organisation.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="98">
	<details>Health and Safety Executive. Mental well-being in the workplace: a resource pack for management training and development. London, Health and Safety Executive Books. 1998.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="99">
	<details>Ambrose, P., Barlow, J. et al. The real cost of poor homes.  pp.1-62. 1996. London, The Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="100">
	<details>Bardsley, M., Jones, I. R. et al. Housing and health in London: a review by the Health of Londoners Project.  1998. London, East London and The City Health Authority.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="101">
	<details>Lowry, S. Housing and health. London, British Medical Journal. 1991: 1-109.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="102">
	<details>Gabe, J. and Williams, P. Women, crowding and mental health in Unhealthy housing: research, remedies and reform Burridge, R. and Ormandy, D., eds. London, E and FN Spon. 1993: pp.191-208.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="103">
	<details>British Medical Association. Deprivation and ill-health.  1987. London, British Medical Association Board of Science and Education Discussion Paper.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="104">
	<details>Smith, S. J., Alexander, A. et al. Rehousing as a health intervention: miracle or mirage? Health and Place,  3 (4) pp.203-216, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="105">
	<details>Allen, T. Housing renewal - doesn't it make you sick? Housing Studies,  15 (3) pp.443-461, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="106">
	<details>Collard, A. Settling up: towards a strategy for resettling homeless families. London, London Homelessness Forum. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="107">
	<details>Atkinson, R. and Kintrea, K. Owner-occupation, social mix and neighbourhood impacts. Policy and Politics,  28 (1) pp.93-108, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="108">
	<details>Dalgard, O. and Tambs, K. Urban environment and mental health: a longitudinal study. Journal of Psychiatry,  171 pp.530-536, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="109">
	<details>Evans, N. S. and Dowler, E. A. Food, health and eating among single homeless and marginalized people in London. Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics,  12 pp.179-199, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="110">
	<details>Halpern, D. Mental health and the built environment: more than bricks and mortar. London, Taylor and Francis. 1995.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="111">
	<details>Hopton, J. and Hunt, S. The health effects of improvements to housing: a longitudinal study. Housing Studies,  11 pp.271-286, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="112">
	<details>Wadham, C. Just what the doctor ordered: a study of housing, health and community safety in Holly Street.  1996. London Borough of Hackney: Estate Management and Development, Holly Street EC1, Woodin Consultancies and Chris Wadham Associates.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="113">
	<details>Health Action for Homeless People. Reaching out: a study of black and ethnic minority single homeless and access to primary care. London, Health Action for Homeless People. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="114">
	<details>Resource Information Service. Hostels: direct access accommodation in London. 1996.  1996. London, London Borough Grants Unit.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="115">
	<details>Susser, E., Lin, S. et al. Risk factors for homelessness among patients admitted to a state mental hospital. American Journal of Psychiatry,  148 (12) pp.1659-1664, 1991</details>
</reference>
<reference key="116">
	<details>Morris, J. N. Inequalities in health: ten years and a little further on. Lancet,  36 pp.491-493, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="117">
	<details>Williams, S. and Allen, I. Health care for single homeless people. London, Policy Studies Institute. 1989.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="118">
	<details>Shelter. Response to the London Strategic Review, October 1997.  1997. London, Shelter.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="119">
	<details>Scheuer, M. The distribution of homeless people in London and their use of acute hospital services in Health and homelessness: research seminar report London, Access to Health. 1992.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="120">
	<details>Black, M., Scheuer, M. et al.  Utilisation by homeless people of acute hospital services in London. British Medical Journal,  303 pp.958-961, 1991</details>
</reference>
<reference key="121">
	<details>Best, R. The housing dimension in Tackling inequalities in health: an agenda for action Benzeval, M., Judge, K. et al., eds. London, King's Fund Publishing. 1995: pp.53-68.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="122">
	<details>Bines, W. The health of single homeless people. Housing Research 128. 1994. York, Centre for Housing Policy, University of York.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="123">
	<details>Goldblatt, P. O. Mortality and alternative social classification in Longitudinal study: mortality and social organisation 1971 - 1981 Goldblatt, P. O., ed. London, HMSO. 1990: pp.164-192.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="124">
	<details>Lamb, R. and Lamb, D. Factors contributing to homelessness among the chronically and severely mentally ill. Hospital and Community Psychiatry,  41 pp.301-305, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="125">
	<details>Lord Clinton-Davis and Fassil, Y. Health and social problems of refugees. Soc.Sci.Med.,  35 (4) pp.507-513, 1992</details>
</reference>
<reference key="126">
	<details>Shiner, M. Adding insult to injury: homelessness and health service use. Sociology of Health and Illness,  14 (4) pp.525-549, 1995</details>
</reference>
<reference key="127">
	<details>Barry, A., Carr-Hill, R. et al. Homelessness and health: what do we know? What should we know? Discussion Paper 84. 1991. York, Centre for Health Economics, University of York.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="128">
	<details>Fisher, B., Hovell, M. et al.  Risks associated with long-term homelessness among women: battery, rape and HIV infection. International Journal of Health Services,   1995</details>
</reference>
<reference key="129">
	<details>Newton, J. and others. Mental health problems of the Edinburgh roofless. British Journal of Psychiatry,  162 pp.537-540, 1994</details>
</reference>
<reference key="130">
	<details>Barker, D., Coggon, D. et al.  Poor housing in childhood and high rates of stomach cancer in England and Wales. British Journal of Cancer,  61 pp.575-578, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="131">
	<details>Artblaster, L. and Hawtin, M. Health, housing and social policy. London, Socialist Health Association. 1993.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="132">
	<details>Boardman, B. Activity levels within the home.  1985. Budapest, Science Policy Research Unit, University of Sussex.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="133">
	<details>Boardmen, B. Fuel poverty. London, Belhaven Press. 1991.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="134">
	<details>Burr, M., Mullins, J. et al. Indoor moulds and asthma. Journal of Research in Social Health,  108 pp.99-101, 1988</details>
</reference>
<reference key="135">
	<details>Martin, C., Platt, S. et al. Housing conditions and ill health. British Medical Journal,  294 pp.1125-1127, 1987</details>
</reference>
<reference key="136">
	<details>Platt, S., Martin, C. et al. Damp housing, mould growth and symptomatic health state. British Medical Journal,  298 pp.1673-1678, 1989</details>
</reference>
<reference key="137">
	<details>Strachan, D. and Elton, R. Relationship between respiratory morbidity in children and the home environment. Family Practice,  3 pp.137-142, 1986</details>
</reference>
<reference key="138">
	<details>Strachan, D. Dampness, mould growth and respiratory disease in children in Unhealthy housing: research, remedies and reform Burridge, R. and Ormandy, D., eds. London, E and FN Spon. 1993.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="139">
	<details>Strachan, D. Damp housing and childhood asthma: validation of reporting of symptoms. British Medical Journal,  297 pp.1223-1226, 1988</details>
</reference>
<reference key="140">
	<details>Todd, S. Danger: a health risk. Community Action,  64 pp.27-29, 1984</details>
</reference>
<reference key="141">
	<details>Child Accident Prevention Trust. Basic principles of child accident prevention. London, Child Accident Prevention Trust. 1989.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="142">
	<details>Constantinides, P. Safe at home? Child accidents and inequality. Radical Community Medicine,  Spring pp.31-33, 1988</details>
</reference>
<reference key="143">
	<details>Department of Trade and Industry. Home and leisure accident research: twelfth annual report, 1988 data.  1991. London, DTI Consumer Safety Unit.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="144">
	<details>Freeman, H. Mental health and high-rise housing in Unhealthy housing: research, remedies and reform Burridge, R. and Ormandy, D., eds. London, E and FN Spon. 1993: pp.168-190.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="145">
	<details>Reading, R., Langford, I. H. et al. Accidents to preschool children: comparing family and neighbourhood risk factors. Soc.Sci.Med.,  48 pp.321-330, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="146">
	<details>Hunt, S. Emotional distress and bad housing. Health and Hygiene,  11 pp.72-79, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="147">
	<details>Walker, R. M. Insecurity and housing consumption in The insecure workforce Heery, E. and Salmon, J., eds. Routledge. 2000.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="148">
	<details>Brennan, M. and Lancashire, R. Association of childhood mortality with housing status and unemployment. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  32 pp.28-33, 1978</details>
</reference>
<reference key="149">
	<details>Nettleton, S. and Burrows, R. When a capital investment becomes an emotional loss: The health consequences of the experience of mortgage possession in England. Housing Studies,  15 (3) pp.463-479, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="150">
	<details>Nettleton, S., Burrows, R. et al. The social consequences of mortgage repossession for parents and their children. Research finding no.829. 1999. York, Joseph Rowntree Foundation. </details>
</reference>
<reference key="151">
	<details>Morse, G. and Calsyn, R. Mentally disturbed homeless people in St. Louis: needy, willing but under-served. Journal of Mental Health,  14 pp.74-94, 1986</details>
</reference>
<reference key="152">
	<details>Keithley, J. and Robinson, F. Violence as a public health issue. Policy and Politics,  28 (1) pp.67-77, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="153">
	<details>Gillies, P. Effectiveness of alliances and partnerships for health promotion. Health Promotion International,  13 pp.99-120, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="154">
	<details>Putnam, R. Making democracy work: civic traditions in modern Italy. New Jersey, Princeton University Press. 1993.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="155">
	<details>Morrow, V. M. Conceptualising social capital in relation to the well-being of children and young people: a critical review. Sociological Review,  47 pp.744-765, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="156">
	<details>Stansfeld, S. A. Social support and social cohesion in Social determinants of health Marmot, M. and Wilkinson, R. G., eds. Oxford, Oxford University Press. 1999: pp.155-178.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="157">
	<details>Cohen, S. and Syme, S. D. L. Social support and health. London, Academic Press. 1985.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="158">
	<details>Cobb, S. Social support as a moderator of life stress. Journal of Psychosomatic Medicine,  38 pp.300-313, 1976</details>
</reference>
<reference key="159">
	<details>Lochner, K., Kawachi, I. et al. Social capital: a guide to its measurement. Health and Place,  5 pp.259-270, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="160">
	<details>Hunter, A. The loss of community: an empirical test through replication. American Sociological Review,  40 pp.537-552, 1975</details>
</reference>
<reference key="161">
	<details>Riger, S. and Lavrakas, P. J. Community ties: patterns of attachment and social interactions in urban neighbourhoods. American Journal of Community Psychology,  9 pp.55-66, 1981</details>
</reference>
<reference key="162">
	<details>Unger, D. and Wandersmann, A. The importance of neighbors: the social cognitive, and affective components of neighboring. American Journal of Community Psychology,  13 pp.139-169, 1983</details>
</reference>
<reference key="163">
	<details>Buckner, J. C. The development of an instrument to measure social cohesion. American Journal of Community Psychology,  16 pp.771-791, 1988</details>
</reference>
<reference key="164">
	<details>Perkins, D. D., Florin, P. et al. Participation and the social and physical environment of neighborhood blocks: crime and community context. American Journal of Community Psychology,  18 pp.83-115, 1990</details>
</reference>
<reference key="165">
	<details>Baum, F. Social capital: is it good for your health? Issues for a public health agenda. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  53 (4) pp.195-196, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="166">
	<details>Berkman, L. and Syme, S. Social networks, host resistance and mortality: a nine-year follow-up study of Alameda County residents. American Journal of Epidemiology,  109 (2) pp.186-204, 1979</details>
</reference>
<reference key="167">
	<details>Burdine, J. N., Felix, M. R. J. et al. Measurement of social capital. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences,  896 pp.393-395, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="168">
	<details>Campbell, C., Wood, R. et al.  Social capital and health. London, Health Education Authority. 1999.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="169">
	<details>Kawachi, I., Kennedy, B. P. et al. Social capital and self-rated health: A contextual analysis. American Journal of Public Health,  89 pp.1187-1193, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="170">
	<details>Kawachi, I. and (and More). A prospective study of social networks in relation to total mortality and cardiovascular disease in men in the USA. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health,  50 pp.245-251, 1996</details>
</reference>
<reference key="171">
	<details>Kawachi, I., Kennedy, B. P. et al. Social capital, income inequality, and mortality. American Journal of Public Health,  87 pp.1491-1498, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="172">
	<details>Leeder, S. and Dominello, A. Social capital and its relevance to health and family policy. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Public Health,  23 pp.424-429, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="173">
	<details>West, P. and Sweeting, H. Health inequalities: what's going on in youth? Health Education,  5 pp.14-20, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="174">
	<details>Runyan, D. K., Hunter, W. M. et al. Children who prosper in unfavorable environments: the relationship to social capital. Pediatrics,  101 (1) pp.12-18, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="175">
	<details>Siahpush, M. and Singh, G. K. Social integration and mortality in Australia. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Public Health,  23 pp.571-577, 1999</details>
</reference>
<reference key="176">
	<details>Veenstra, G. Social capital, SES and health: an individual-level analysis. Soc.Sci.Med.,  50 pp.619-629, 2000</details>
</reference>
<reference key="177">
	<details>Cattell, V. and Evans, M. Neighbourhood images in East London: social capital and social networks on two East London estates. York, YPS for the Joseph Rowntree Foundation. 1999: 1-61.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="178">
	<details>Moser, C. and McIlwaine, C. Gender and rebuilding social capital in the context of political violence and conflict in Colombia and Guatemala in (forthcoming) Gender, armed conflict and political violence Moser, C. and Clark, F., eds. London, Zed. 2000.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="179">
	<details>Uphoff, N. Giving theoretical and operational content to social capital. New York, Mimeo, Cornell University. 1997.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="180">
	<details>North, D. Institutions, institutional change and economic performance. Cambridge and New York, Cambridge University Press. 1990.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="181">
	<details>Fukuyama, F. Trust: the social virtues and the creation of prosperity. London, Penguin. 1995.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="182">
	<details>Harriss, J. and De Renzio, P. An introductory bibliographic essay. 'Missing link' or 'analytically missing? The concept of social capital. Journal of International Development,  9 (7) pp.919-937, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="183">
	<details>Putzel, J. Accounting for the 'dark side' of social capital: reading Robert Putnam on democracy. Journal of International Development,  9 (7) pp.939-949, 1997</details>
</reference>
<reference key="184">
	<details>Portes, A. Social capital: its origins and applications in modern sociology. American Review of Sociology,  24 (1) pp.1-24, 1998</details>
</reference>
<reference key="185">
	<details>Lederman, D., Loayza, N. et al. Violent crime: does social capital matter? Washington D.C., World Bank, Poverty Reduction and Management Network. 1999.</details>
</reference>
<reference key="186">
	<details>Wolff, S. P. and Gillham, C. J. Public health versus public policy? An appraisal of British urban transport policy. Public Health,  105 pp.217-228, 1991</details>
</reference>
<reference key="187">
	<details>McIntyre, L. and Petticrew, M. Methods of health impact assessment: a literature review. Occasional Paper Number 2, pp.1-110. 1999. Glasgow, MRC Social and Public Health Sciences Unit. </details>
</reference>
</records>
